NOEL AMADOR LUNA

+1 512.558.1023 • noelamadorluna@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/noelamadorluna • github.com/nluna96/

Self-driven and attentive professional with 3+ years of experience in technical client-facing projects. Highly motivated and skilled in building relationships with partners, internal teams, and vendors to achieve desired business outcomes.

Key skills:

- Project Planning
- Conflict Resolution
- Risk Management
- Cross-Cultural Team Building
- Interpersonal Communication Skills
- Retrospective-Based Teamwork
- Self-Management

- Client Relationship & Governance
- Product Design & Development
- Meetings Management
- Documentation Maintenance
- Trilingual (Spanish, French, and English)
- Strategic Thinking

CAREER PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS-----

Wells Fargo (Client Technical Analyst, Experian). Assigned to be the technical lead for the Wells Fargo project. Tested and provided feedback to custom API workflow for Wells Fargo Program Manager. Collaborated with Experian Sales Director, Program Manager, and Sales Engineer to initiate a partnership with Wells Fargo, bringing in 30 million dollars over three years.

Discover Financial Services (Technical Solutions Intern, Experian). Worked alongside Discover Product Owner to launch new products for Discover. Provided test data, testing APIs, and worked with an internal Project Manager to estimate a launch date for new product. There are about 700,000 members using services and products I implement.

Truebill (Client Technical Analyst, Experian). Drafted strategy and recommendation plans to choose the best APIs for a project. Developed custom monitoring services to keep track and analyze API workflows for Truebills 800,000 subscribers.

Work Experience-----

Client Technical Analyst | Experian Austin, TX

February 2020 - September 2021

- Performs requirements gathering through communication with client and internal teams to build comprehensive implementation solutions
- Interfaces with product and tech support teams to ensure the smooth deployment of new features and fixes through QA testing and analysis
- Assists Account and Project Managers with new client and product implementations for existing clients

Technical Solutions Intern | Experian Austin, TX

August 2019 - November 2019

- Shadowed Senior Client Technical Analysts through client calls (documented and monitored requirements needed to institute proposed updates in relation to customer experience, and provided detailed specifications for proposed solutions including time and scope involved)
- Worked alongside internal team to provide test data and QA testing for clients
- Proactively documented new client workflows

Project Coordinator Intern | Experian Austin, TX

May 2019 - August 2019

- Coordinated technical skill trainings for project managers
- Met with project team members to identify and resolve issues
- Worked alongside Senior Project Managers to define project scope, goals, and deliverables
- Met with clients to take detailed ordering briefs and clarify specific requirements for each project

IT Intern | Consulate General of Mexico Austin, TX

February 2019 - May 2019

- Provided bilingual services to internal teams and external vendors
- Provided orientation and guidance to users on how to operate new software and computer equipment
- Performed troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve problems (repair or replace parts, debugging, etc.)
- Maintained records/logs of repairs, fixes, and maintenance schedule

College Assistant Migrant Program Mentor | St. Edward's University Austin, TX June 2017 – June 2019

- Mentored college freshman by providing students with periodic performance review, referral to Universities academic and health resources, and facilitated students transition into college
- Assisted supervisor with interviewing new mentor applicants
- · Served as a mandated reporter

Field Laborer | Brownfield, TX

Seasonal June - August: 2012-2015

- Provided company with fast-paced agriculture production through long shifts of manual labor in order to meet company's production deadlines
- Provided bilingual services for supervisor
- Supervised teams of 15 workers

Awards-----

- St. Edward's University College Assistance Migrant Program Scholarship recipient (2015-2019)
- Hatton Sumner Scholarship recipient (2016-2019)
- Johnson Turpin Scholarship recipient (2016-2019)

Affiliations-----

- Experian Toastmasters (2020-2021)
- Experian Juntos ERG (2020-2021)
- Alpha Mu Gamma member [Language Honor Society] (2017-2019)
- St. Edward's University French Club member (2016-2019)
- St. Edward's University Computer Science Club member (2015-2019)
- St. Edward's Intramural Flag Football member (2015-2019)
- St. Edward's Intramural Soccer member (2015-2019)
- College Forward member (2013-2019)

Volunteer-----

- Junior Achievements (2020-2021)
- Austin Animal Center (2016-2019)
- College Forward Mentor (2018)

EDUCATION & TRAINING------

The University of Manchester | Manchester, England

September 2021 - Current

MSc Business Analysis and Strategic Management

The University of Texas at Austin | Austin, TX

Data Analysis and Visualization Bootcamp at Texas McCombs

St. Edward's University | Austin, TX

December 2019

April 2021

B.S. Computer Science & Minor in French

 In summer of 2017, I completed an immersive French language program at Université Catholique de l'Ouest in Anger, France

Languages

Spanish - Native Speaker English - Full Professional Proficiency French - Intermediate Mid

Trainings

Data Visualization Tableau Training, 2019